Roberto Gambuzzi

• Co Dublin, Ireland

☑ gambuzzi@gmail.com

**** 083 838 0077

• www.gambuzzi.it

in gambuzzi

Dublin, Ireland Jan 2022 - present

Summary _

Coding from the age of 8, I have 25+ year of coding work experience. I worked with a lot of languages, a lot of hardware, a lot of technologies. Less known (Anoto digital Paper), and mainstream ones (Magento Ecommerce). Still on my path to learn. "I know that I do not know"

Experience _

Toast, Principal Software Engineer

- Part of the Reporting, Analytics, and Machine Learning Team
- Part of Dataplatform Team
- Toast is leader in the field of all-in-one software for restaurant.
- In my role, I collaborate with the reporting team to tackle the intricate challenge of generating comprehensive reports from an extensive dataset spanning multiple PetaBytes, using technologies such as PostgreSQL, Spark, Parquet, Zeppelin, Python, and DynamoDb.

Google, Senior Software Engineer

• Implementing new features for the AMP (accelerated mobile pages) and managing the automations around the Google Search Fleet autoscaling logic.

Dublin, Ireland July 2021 - Jan 2022

FabFitFun, Principal Software Engineer

• FabFitFun is a subscription e-commerce with millions of customers.

• I designed the new internal services that replaced the 3rd party ones, also leading the migration from a monolithic approach to a microservices oriented one

Dublin, Ireland Jan 2020 - July 2021

Dublin, Ireland Apr 2018 - Jan 2020

Dublin, Ireland Jan 2016 - Apr 2018

Vectra.ai, Principal Software Engineer

- Vectra.ai is a company leader in the field of cyber-security.
- I designed and created a system able to ingest Terabytes of data per day, allowing customers to perform sophisticated queries for threat hunting and in-
- I speed up the old ingestion process by 10 times.
- I wrote the internal single sign on system.

Amazon AWS, Senior Software Engineer

- I designed and realized the automation process for the deployment of Redshift in new AWS regions.
- I created a common API backend to centralize all of the different APIs in the networking layer of Amazon.
- I wrote UI React Components for the internal networking web tools.

Webgriffe, Senior Software Engineer

- Webgriffe is an Italian company leader in the Magento e-commerces field.
- I was working on e-commerces and I created numerous importing script for catalogs of many different types of products.
- I was in charge of optimizing existing e-commerces, reporting process, enabling efficient data retrieval, analysis, and presentation, while maintaining optimal performance and responsiveness.

MGC s.r.l., Senior Software Engineer

• Python, C#, Delphi, MSSQL, Anoto Digital Paper

Casalgrande (RE), Italy Feb 2011 - Dec 2015

Modena, Italy

2008 - 2011

Roberto Gambuzzi - Page 1 of 2

GBIT s.r.l., Senior Software Engineer and analystPython, java, mysql	Sassulo (MO), Italy 2007 – 2008
I.T.C.G. "Baggi", Information Technology Teacher	Modena, Italy 2005 – 2006
Dreamtech s.n.c., Freelance DeveloperPython, MySQL, PHP, MSSQL	Modena, Italy 2002 – 2007
 ASTARTE Sistemi Grafici s.a.s., Junior software developer Borland C++ 	Modena, Italy 2001 – 2002
G7 Elaborazione Dati s.r.l., Junior software developerAccess, C, C++	Sassuolo (MO), Italy 2001 – 2002
Studio Sikorski, Junior software developer • PERL, cgi e-commerces	Carpi (MO), Italy 1998 – 1999

Education _____

Diploma

Università di Bologna, Information Technology

Bologna, Italy
1997 – 2001

I.T.I.S. "F. Corni", Head technician, computer technology

Thesis on video signals sampling with limited hardware

Bologna, Italy
1997 – 2001

Technologies _

Languages: Python, Java, Kotlin, Rust, GO, PHP, Javascript, SQL

Technologies: AWS, PostgreSQL, REST APIs, Kubernetes, Embedded systems, SparkSQL, Elastic Search, Redshift, Performance Testing, MySQL, NodeJs, Azure

Languages _____

English: Fluent **Italian:** Native

Open Source Contributions _____

argoproj/argo-cd: argoproj/argo-cd
prasmussen/gdrive: prasmussen/gdrive

lmammino/rust-advent: lmammino/rust-advent

tehmaze/diagram: tehmaze/diagram